<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://daniel.feldroy.com/</id>
  <title>Til posts by Daniel Roy Greenfeld</title>
  <updated>2025-05-06T07:53:36.895809+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Daniel Roy Greenfeld</name>
    <email>daniel@feldroy.com</email>
    <uri>https://daniel.feldroy.com</uri>
  </author>
  <link href="https://daniel.feldroy.com" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://daniel.feldroy.com/images/pydanny-cartwheel.png</logo>
  <rights>All rights reserved 2025, Daniel Roy Greenfeld</rights>
  <entry>
    <id>https://daniel.feldroy.com/posts/til-2025-05-reverse-square-knot</id>
    <title>TIL: Reverse Square Knot</title>
    <updated>2025-05-06T07:53:36.895949+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Roy Greenfeld</name>
      <email>daniel@feldroy.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For years I've used a basic square knot to tie my belt in various martial arts. The problem is that while I tie it neatly, it always comes undone. It doesn't matter if was the stand-up striking arts of my younger years or the   grappling-focused Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu I do now - the knot always comes undone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew of a better knot, but I never knew what it was called or how to do it. I heard references to superlock, Gracie knots, and a few other names. I finally today learned that the better knot is officially called a "reverse square knot," also known as a right square knot or reverse reef knot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The improved knot is an incredible upgrade, meaning I can focus on my training rather than worrying about my belt coming undone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the proof of my first good attempt, a photo I took after a &lt;strong&gt;2 hour class where it never came undone&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="reverse-square-knot" src="/public/images/reverse-square-knot.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: I had just sparred a few rounds and the belt got twisted. Ignore the twists and just admire the still-tied belt.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do a martial art with Judo-style belts (these include Karate, Tae Kwon Do, and Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu), I highly recommend you learn this knot. It's a simple change that can make a big difference in your training experience. This video is a good place to start: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bex5a95gG8U"&gt;How to Tie a Reverse Square Knot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://daniel.feldroy.com/posts/til-2025-05-reverse-square-knot"/>
    <summary>Useful for martial arts with belts, a "reverse square knot," also known as a right square knot or reverse reef knot, is essentially a square knot tied in the opposite order. Instead of the first working cord going over the other cords, it goes under them first.</summary>
    <category term="TIL"/>
    <category term="martial arts"/>
    <category term="bjj"/>
    <contributor>
      <name>Daniel Roy Greenfeld</name>
      <email>daniel@feldroy.com</email>
    </contributor>
    <published>2025-05-06T15:50:48.417058+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
